set up the gear. We hope it works well.
I hope I can display that my knowledge
on the fuel cell is better than my
knowledge of setting up projectors. So,
without any further ado, I've produced a
little movie. It's about 20 minutes
long. It has a lot of cutaways and shows
other vision that it would take me far
longer to to display to you. So, best
thing is let's play the movie and come
back to it afterwards.
Hi Steve, this is Steve James [music]
the author of the book Water Fuel Cell
Secrets Revealed. Steve you're here
today to minister into something
secret.
Um
what you can do
uh take
very basic concept yourself
develop
formulas and theories
and make the process repeatable
opposed to having an idea or a concept
that really had no basis. people were
just unable to to communicate with
others just what they achieved other
than than referring to BS.
Um the fuel cell what is uh
what is it? Well, it's placed in a
number of stainless steel cylinders and
tubes
inside [clears throat] the other uh
water field
and a process of extracting energy from
the water.
So, what's the history of?
Well,
initially it was was discovered
They came across [music] this trying to
walk system
and change the shape of his we
for seem to work quite well. So Joe was
not able to bring it to um to any great
degree relative great degree. Uh I
really don't know a lot about
the interest in other fields and fields.
I've seen videos where he expressed
um that he didn't really know what the
energy was or how it worked, but it did
work. And that's what got me originally
interested. It was a phenomena that not
only Joe and others had been
had results with people who made engines
run.
So what have you done to um that perhaps
others haven't done in the past with
towards the development of the pure
self?
What I tried to do from from the
beginning
was to create formulas um methods of
measuring and methods of communicating.
So instead of um selling other people,
it all works on BS which has never been
the case. We're only involved with with
these people charging sales and
primarily
was all about what was on top of the
water.
I wasn't really happy with trying to
work with BS and it's pretty hard to say
somebody myself working.
What I did was
look a little closer at the electronic
aspects of the cell. What was happening
when I charged it? What happened after I
charged? Uh did did the voltage that
that the cell go across it? Did that
diminish instantly? Did it take time?
And what I found was there was a direct
relationship between the decay voltage
across the sample and the state of
charge.
Uh we were able to I was able to uh
build a a computer interface, write a
program,
charge the cell and then monitor it the
state of charge on the cell over. It
turned out to be many many months and
then established that there was not any
relationship between the state of charge
uh of the cell and the voltage that was
across it. But it was a relationship
that met the requirements of formula. I
was able to uh
create a formula that would say okay do
these measurements of these high levels
and
you can tell exactly how much charge is
in the cell or isn't in the cell. You
can also tell whether the cell is
leaking, whether we've got uh problems
where it's not holding a charge. uh and
none of these uh things were available
previously.
>> So what are the elements that are needed
to have a working fuel cell?
Uh or three criteria. The first is the
water. The water's got to be the right
water. Now when I say right water, I
developed a method of processing that
water or any to usable. Uh the second is
the construction of the cell needs to be
constructed within certain criteria, the
right certain metals and the right
thickness.
Uh and then the water is put in the cell
and the cell is energized by applying a
series of voltages until we uh cause the
deteriorate
into the steel.
Okay. about the water. What's water
table? There's something special about
the water.
Well, it's not that it's special water.
We just need water at the right right
part of the process. And although I
explain that a lot in the book, um
ideal water has often been called fresh
or juvenile water. Well, that's water
that's virtually just rain out of the
top of the stream somewhere. Problem
with that is it's almost impossible to
find. And even if you do find the right
location, the water you get there is
very different the day after a
thunderstorm to the day in the middle of
a drought. So, what I tried to do was
look at exactly what made water the
right water. First, we needed to have as
little contaminants as possible. And
we're not talking manmade contaminants.
We're talking uh
carbon type contaminants. We need the
water to have a reasonably conductivity.
Pure water doesn't conduct and therefore
doesn't put in electrolysis. So that's
not not going to work. Um
we need the pH of the water to be
relatively neutral, slightly acidic. If
anything, certainly not as alkaline as
it can be way downstream.
What I did was to develop a process
involving ionization where we separate
the water from its normal 10 to 13
molecules into six molecule classes
and in that process we're able to
extract what we don't want from the
water being long chain carbons and
the process doesn't really affect the
conductivity of the water or change the
pH. So what it means is that almost any
natural water By that I mean
nonprocessed water can now be used be
rain water, stream, creek, river water,
uh anywhere like that can now be
processed to the point where it's using
a cell.
Interesting. Um, so the cell itself,
what's now? What's about the cell
itself? How is it made? What's it made
of? Well, many things have been tried.
The best is stainless steel. There's no
doubt about that. A good cell will be
made in 360, which is a low carb, high
ground stance. The primary reason for
that is that it doesn't deteriorate too
much with the electrolysis which is a
primal part of of conditioning the cell.
Uh we don't have problems with corrosion
and rust. Um
the main thing with a successful cell is
having reasonably heavy metal. Doesn't
matter the cathode or the neutrals and
silver within the cell. The cell casing
itself either needs to be of a
substantial metal or have a fairly good
good top solid top solid top ring
assembly where the energy is taken
1.6 for 2 mil is fine. It's reasonably
important that the status is not
magnetic. we really just will not get
the results if it's if it's highly
magnetized
which is the reason going for 316
stainless. The other thing is that
I found that the seams or welding and
cell construction is is a big negative.
It really does affect the operation of
the cell.
Currently I use seamless stainless and I
find that is is by far better and a
pressure assemble cell where quite
literally the tops and bottoms are
pressed in
um in a fashion that we don't
and we have no no welding which affects
the working structure of the metal and
therefore affects the energy that flows
through it. So in having the cell and
the water and obviously getting them
together,
how do you actually get the cell to
work?
That's that's a three-state stage
process. The first thing is to have
yourself acceptable properly and clean
um to put in the charged water where the
water is has been processed and
electrically charged.
We first pull the water into the soil.
will then go through a stage of
energizing which is applying a voltage
for a given time and duration at a given
intervals according to the uh the
formula is the charge charge power
formula. Um and we we charge the cell
until its half life which is another one
of the formulas until it halfife stops
extending other words we have a fixed
half life at that point tip out the
water it's always got contaminants in it
mainly contaminants from the surface of
the stainless
putting fresh water uh and and it's time
to start using the energy from the cell
in the running
And is that all we need to do?
Seal thing that the water contain in the
glass forever or does it evaporate away
or uh the cell can't be sealed would
probably
it simply cannot electrolysis we create
gases hydrogen and oxygen the primary
gases. Um not a lot of gas certainly not
enough to run the engine in any fashion
even the smallest engine could run. So
the people that think that we've got a
hydrogen generator not happen near
enough. If we had no means of that gas
getting out there that would be enough
to create pressure and eventually
explode. So we do have to have a a vent
and that vent must be fed through a ho
or hydrogen flashback
so that the gases that are produced can
be vented from the cell um safely. And
in my case, I always run the out of the
flashback
engines in that manifold and feed into
the vacuum and dispose of it quite
nicely and get to shoot in the engine.
Having said that, I've done a number of
tests where I've disconnected that
vacuum or closed it off the engine end
[clears throat] satisfied that it's it's
having no measurable effect on the
engine. We're not using any energies
associated with the gas.
Then so here we have a a fuel cell which
is producing um dutarium which actually
gets the motor to work. How does that
get to the motor? How does it work
within the motor?
>> Okay. Well my theory is that the at the
point of electrolysis we've got gases
coming off of what effectively the two
electrodes the cathode being the center
of the cell. The anode is the other
case.
At the point where the gas is coming off
of the out case which is positive, we've
got oxygen gas being produced and
against the stainless steel warm off the
the case. We have effectively hydrogen
enriched water. I believe that the
positive voltage applied to
permit the electrolysis
attracts the hydrogen. When I say
hydrogen, we're possibly talking
detracted
to the molecular structure, the
crystallized structure of the steel
itself
and migrates through the structure um
toward the source of voltage. Now coming
off the top of the cell we have a
connection device to the engine. Um
for the most part in the past that has
has typically been a tube uh 1 in round
a fairly heavy tubing
uh where people were thinking it was a
gas that was actually going through the
tube.
Although that tube was not vented into
the engine. It was going to a blind
connection on the engine. meaning that
at the point where the tube met the
engine was no hole going through. We
were simply presenting this gas to a
blind plug. Um I then thought one more
and more is it actually gas at that
point. Is it traveling through the the
hole through the metal? Another test
that I did that led me to the to the
conclusion that it actually migrates
through the steel itself.
And one from the tube was to use a head
alter
19 cable to connect the cell to the
engine. Now we go out of the the engine
as explaining in detail in the book. But
what we do is we use a voltage which is
connected at the engine cable and that
attracts this energy along the cable
right up to the the point of the engine
where it travels over a small gap into
the block itself or the cylinder head.
Mhm. Uh and then over time do the entire
engine
with the hydrogen deter
referium
because I really don't have a method for
telling you exactly what it is. It
simply fits with uh what I believe to be
the operation of the engine.
>> Then once this is within the engine
within the metal itself, how does it
then work the combust?
Okay. Well,
what I believe happens is different to
any of the other theories being
presented. It's just what I think.
is that we end up with our combustion
chamber effectively being totally doped
with hydrogen deterior.
So that all surfaces
effectively wet with these uh these
elements.
When we then combust or or start to
compress atmosphere, which is almost
sucking into the engine, just air uh at
about two 2 and 1 half atmospheres
within spark where ignition timing is no
longer a few degrees before top dead
center. It's around 70° uh and and only
85. So the pistons just over halfway up
the stroke the spark happens that would
seem to create that inflation.
Now there are suggestions and I've read
information that suggests that if we don
in hydrogen enriched environment which
is what we really have with air in this
enriched combustion chamber we get a
thermic reaction which is the implosion.
Now that implosion was certainly
explained for the effect of compression
being removed. the fact that the engine
can turn out so slowly and so easily.
Uh that implosion would draw the piston
up and possibly also make the valve
leak. In the normal for engine valves
are intended to seal under compressions,
not under vacuums.
So it also sucks in more atmosphere that
was intended to go into the chamber.
And the other interesting point with an
endothermic reaction is that endothermic
reactions consume the heat of the
inflation. Now we also explain why so
many people have reported these engines
running cold.
I personally had um a read of 70° C on
the exhaust of my generator.
Um 70 is not that cold. You can put your
hand on it if you want to. Yes. When you
say generating your home petrol driven
motor generator test you got a small
I haven't
given
me producing apply that to normal for
what people were going for
out and so on. So the generator seems to
be on four bands perfect way of testing.
Uh back to to the operation of the
engine, it would seem that if we've got
an end reaction happening in implosion
that's pulling more atmosphere than uh
would normally be the case. When the
piston approaches the top, there's a
release of energy from that implosion.
And I really don't know through what
process, but that explosion definitely
takes place. So we have the implosion at
the bottom of the or halfway up the
stroke somewhere around top dead center
without see there's definite explosion
that is visible watching the engine run
the firewise
if we were running pula
although it's fair to say there's a
great reduction in the noise of the
engine is a lot quieter greater rate on
cell than it would be on petrol. Um that
could be explained by the fact that the
explosion component is a shorter shorter
duration than a normal petrol explosion.
Most of the noise that we hear from a
four- stroke engine's exhaust is in fact
the exhaust valve opening. There's still
pressure there and that comes out
through the valve exhaust and so on. In
this case, it's quite a reduction in
that noise. Um, so that's basically how
it works.
>> And is this engine running with petrol
as well or just purely on air or mixture
of both still? Well, I have never
managed to start the generator without
petrol. I have to be [clears throat]
absolutely honest about that. Some
people have claimed that they can start
and operate engines from cells alone. I
haven't. It has always taken petrol.
Having said that, it's a full start and
there's a limit to how many times you
can pull that shred and try to get it
going. So, I'm quite happy with the idea
of putting a little bit of petrol in a
in a much smaller than normal tank.
Um, and getting getting the engine
running down there exactly how long it
run for with petrol turned off. uh and
there is there is little doubt for much
much longer than that is possible not
only from myself of course but but many
friends neighbors and other people have
seen that um
that's not really what I'm looking to
promote. It's it's only fair to say that
it's a very new science. It certainly
isn't perfected. Anyone building a cell
uh and going down this this avenue would
be foolish to believe they're going to
build the cell, start the generator, run
for forever. We're not there yet.
>> We're getting closer with some of the
formulas and methods of communicating.
We're now in a position to to further
the science by exchanging what
information we're learning
as we go. And uh so you've you've been
able to develop a a working model and
demonstrate that it works. Where you
moving to from there?
I I think at this stage it's a case of
of refining what I have established. Um
the formulas seem seem to be consistent
and working.
There are certainly atmospheric effects
of um I haven't haven't yet proven
conclusively
but I find the best uncanny that I can
never get the thing to run. It's not
outside it's inside
but uh there certainly effects of
humidity of the engine. So one of my
directions is to look at the condition
or condition of atmosphere as it goes
in.
Um
as far as the cells construction itself,
we are exploring with
the idea of lining different metals so
that we can obtain great mass energy to
go through um while still having the
stainless steel containers. Uh of course
it's always the normal thing. it's
expensive for research. Um, another
component that I would like to to
research is the concept of incorporating
a cell within a motor instead of being a
separate device that's brought to the
motor. the idea of actually
incorporating the generation of the
hydrogen materials within the water
cooling confinements of the engine. And
again, something
[clears throat]
here was just me, you know.
Now I'm hoping you all got some
questions for me there. Yes. Uh I
presume when you run out of petrol the
engine still running. Have you done an
exhaust gas analysis run the results?
>> No.
>> The other question is how do you start
the engine on petrol 70°?
>> Do you get no firing or no?
>> You just don't get compression the
implosion.
>> No. No. when you when you started your
first petrol.
>> Yes.
>> How do you start with 70°?
>> You still with petrol once the energy
from the center reass
if I didn't fully that spot that
didn't fire until top dead center. If I
had it on
30°
so 70°
start
85 or 90
>> 85 90°
how do you start the engine on petrol?
>> You never you can never just have the
engine on petrol and I say start we put
petrol in the materium is always
present. So from the very beginning we
get an endothermic reaction out of
enclosure. There's no perceivable
compression when you pull the string the
plates in.
You have no perceivable compression in
pulling the string. It's simply
you get the inertia turning over the
crack the mass you get to the point
where the engine fires as the string
gets pushed out. There is you've
experienced this Bob. Bob's been there
many times when we started this. Uh
there is no compression and therefore
normally any any internal combustion
engine trying to idle at low revs with
20 or 30° the thing will just fire. The
piston will get stalled or go backwards.
It won't run. With one of these you can
go from uh top dead center back to 90°
before top halfway up stroke and the
engine just turns over. There's
definitely an implosion component that
happens before the explosion
present. Even with it present. Yes.
Yeah. But I can't get it where I pull
the string and starts without petrol. I
need petrol there initially to get the
revs up. And it only needs to be enough
petrol for the thing to rev and then it
can run out of petrol. But the problem
is you can't pull it fast enough to get
it to self run. One of those engines
where you've got those start
release on it. So that you're not full
compression. Yeah. So as soon as it
fires
compression
building compression at all otherwise
you wouldn't be able to start that
doesn't have any sort of depression. It
hasn't no we have a book which is what
I'm promoting tonight that has pictures
of that very engine the cylinder head.
You can see the valves and it's quite
easy to look at it. It's an oldfashioned
you know four stroke engine. It's quite
a few years old. Um it's not designed to
run with a sort of an advanced timing
that it has. It shouldn't be possible.
It simply shouldn't be right. And the
only way it does is because of the ender
reaction, an implosion that happens.
>> No, I was going to.
>> Not tonight.
>> We were hoping tonight, but these things
take time.
What what's the relationship between
your voltage and your amp?
You finding that running small voltage
or high ampage. What are we talking in
the cell?
>> In the cell itself.
>> Um that particular cell with with the
wood I'm using about 250 300 milliamps
12 volt.
>> Is there any in the cell?
>> No, not not a power. It's only three W
or something.
>> [clears throat]
>> What happens if you actually press the
the air press?
>> You you don't really need to um
with with a cell and this is where a lot
of people that have that have built
water fuel cells or chose cells where a
lot of things have gone wrong is they've
been chasing bubbles and we don't need
bubbles and and therefore the amount of
electrolysis we need is a fraction of
what people thought we needed. We start
off by putting charged water into the
cell. So it's fully charged before we
put it in there. From then on, every
voltage that we apply to the cell is a
conditioning voltage to get the dutium
from the water into the steel.
>> So about some of the cells where they're
using
>> well they're not working. They're
looking for
whatever.
No, Joseph certainly isn't looking for
that. And I mentioned in the in the
video that the gas that comes off of one
of these things is so so minuscule
position will display the um the the uh
screen
uh on the computer that shows the
condition of the cell. You've got a
fairly elaborate um piece of software
and hardware.
>> Yes, but I can't bring I guess I didn't
bring my computer systems.
>> Okay, fair enough.
>> Uh there was a quick glimpse of it.
>> I started off like everybody else did
with with Joel. I saw something on the
internet. I water and and I start off
the hard way and I went through and I
got up in the middle of night and
charged water for 3 minutes went back to
sleep for two more hours and like a lot
of you that have played with Joe says
it's better takes a lot of time. I then
thought there's going to be an easier
way. So I bu interface [clears throat]
um I then wrote some software that could
do variations on charging and what I
realized was there is a relationship
between the residual voltage in the cell
and the conditional or the charge of the
cell. So I came up with what I call a
full life and a half life formula. Now
what that that means is that we can
charge any cell with any water for 1
minute just straight 12 V and then we
can measure that voltage 1 minute later
and that's called our full life voltage.
We can wait another 4 minutes and
measure what that voltage has dropped
off to and that is our halflife voltage.
Now every time we charge the cell and we
do that in accordance with another very
simple formula. Every time we charge the
cell, it takes longer for that halflife
voltage to drop off. So, initially,
because of how the formula worked, it's
5 minutes, but it's not long before it's
25 minutes, and then it's an hour. So,
we're charging it the same amount of
charge each time, but the duration
between the charge gets longer and
longer, and that's to do with the the
surface charge, the material in the
surface of the steel being absorbed into
the crystallite structure.
So, it it's quite an interesting
formula. What it does, it takes all the
guess work out and all of you people
that have have charged looking for
bubbles. The simple formula will get
those wonderful bubbles within a day or
so very easily repeatedly.
Do
>> you find that um
effectiveness of the cell increased with
the engine?
>> Sorry, with the load applied to the
>> No, I can't say I've really tested that.
Um
>> could you repeat the questions on
>> Okay. The gentleman asked whether um
there was an increase in effectiveness
of the wood fuel cell on the engine when
a load was applied to the engine. Um
it's it's not something that I tested to
date. I always run the generator. I say
always that's not true. Most of the time
I run the generator the load. Uh you saw
in the video a little 250 W hogen lamp
on the generator. Uh the reason for that
is that even the fuel with the car in
one of these things will make it run for
several minutes without a lot of idle.
You don't use a whole lot of juice.
Well, I I'll tell you why I asked that
question because when I experimented
with the job set, I had um I was
expecting the um the car basically to
run and id like most people do and um I
was able to to increase the on
the idle time on just one float chamber
of content to uh about 6 and 1/2
minutes, but normally it's about 1 and
1/2 minutes, which I thought there very
good but I was never left up when I was
trying to run the engine. Uh then under
load I wasn't able to turn turn the fuel
off until one day when I was going about
100 km an hour and I had written the
load on the engine and just because I
had a fuel just turn it off. Yep. And it
would then keep running enough I drove
for about 10 15 km and then as soon as
the load dropped below a certain level
that it I had to turn the fuel on again
because there was it would only work
above a certain load not below. So I was
able to actually drive with a fuel up
inclines and not up the freeway and all
that. Not actually driving under under
low conditions. And that was for a year
[clears throat]
advance on the distributor itself. What
sort of timing you
>> I don't I I don't know other than I know
that I had to actually um the machine
the foot got the distributor away
because the the um slot wasn't long
enough was it was way way past
>> but but that was um after quite a while
initially there's no way you can get
running after the sale was on there for
[clears throat] quite quite a few weeks.
So you had advanced timing. Did you have
any problems with it or
>> No trouble with the flight?
>> No, I did not. But that was no
condition, but it would only really work
under
a certain when they when I was doing
about 65 km an hour constant turn the
fuel off in the bath but not below which
is which is counter to what you would
expect. That's why I'm asking the
question. There there definitely seems
to be a change in in the air
requirements of the engine. Uh a short
part of the video there I didn't think
to make it obvious.
>> It it may not be more air. It might be
less air. When you look at the load
situation and in fact the car is open um
on the generator here part of the filing
that you saw it running there was a
thumb
almost nowhere over the car that was Bob
Cox's thumb blocking off the air intake
[clears throat] to the car. Now normal
generator refs blow on it and the
carburetor virtually blocked off choke
butterfly closed
box thumb which is bigger than mine. his
thumb was able to fit the whole hole.
Virtually no air going into this engine.
It shouldn't have even been able to run
at those reps and yet it did and it
would not run with normal gun. Another
strange thing happens to me all the time
is petrol won't flow into it. Doesn't
matter what I do, I cannot get the
petrol to go into the carburetor. It's
like it's blocked, but it isn't. Uh and
that seems to be when there's too much
energy there. It just repels the petrol
flow.
So, but we're getting there.
Okay. Another question. Um, you've got
250 W
and I've seen it myself. You say you
have about 6 minutes worth of
[clears throat] in
the maximum time the machine has run
powering that once you start to shut the
fuel off. People have heard that
I'll say an hour because many people
have seen the hour. It's longer, but an
hour is is and to me for something like
this to run for an hour without a fuel
tank connected, it's pretty complicated.
Yes.
>> Have you thought of any way how do you
might concentrate the so-called dutyium
before in the water before you actually
start electrolizing at all or anything
like that?
>> Uh I don't know there's a need to when
you um charge water repeatedly keep
charging it becomes heavy water enriched
water. Um
and and that really seems to be enough.
But when we put it into the cell, the
actual electrolysis that's happening in
the cell is also charging that water and
creating more deterior. So how do we get
deterior? Well, we know that all natural
water has it. [clears throat] It's it's
just there.
We know that when we charge water
through electrolysis, we create more
deterior. Now the only difference
between hydrogen deterior is an electron
neutron. Uh we do know that in
electrolysis we're separating hydrogen
effectively oxygen. Oxygen's got uh
seven or eight neutrons. Someone tell me
>> eight. Thank you. I get these numbers.
I'm electronics guy. Some of this stuff
is just beyond me. But you have to learn
it if you try to be sure. Um so we we've
got all the components to make material
and I think science is quite happy with
the fact that we do by charging water.
Another thing is an idea of how much
deterium do we need for it to actually
go through metal. I'm talking did you
have a blind connection on your engine
or did you go to that
>> blind blind connection to just
aluminum
uh block with about 1/2 in double it and
that's where
>> okay so the energy is going through the
metal itself how much do we need 1/8 of
a g of detium is the equivalent of 1200
L of petrol
so it gives you some idea of the bang
that you get in detium Now on my engine
there [clears throat]
microphone but it's a blind connection.
So okay I do feed back into the cell and
this is the typically the cell that was
on the roof.
Come back to the microphone. I feed a
vacuum through this very very small
diameter tube. Occasionally I block this
thing off and also the test to make sure
that we're not running or having
anything to do with the gas that's
coming out of here. Very little but it's
there. Um,
no more tubes. This is solid cable.
Okay. So, we're [clears throat] actually
connecting to the engine via 19 aluminum
cable and that energy is going through
there. Uh, Ian Pagan, some of you would
know who new put one of these exact
cells on on his car a couple of days
ago. There's a video on on YouTube now.
Um, he did tests on on this little
Corolla which hadn't had a sale on in
the past. uh he ran it many many times
and and he got 90
90 something seconds repeatedly uh by
switching off the fuel. The first thing
he did before he put a cell on there was
put a fuel cup so soft started ran it
turned off the fuel time it repeated and
repeated and repeated and got exactly
the same time. Then he put a cell on
there in his case the the cable is way
wrong. Um, hooked it up. Couple of
energizing charges,
then turned the fuel off. We got 4
minutes and 5 seconds.
>> Just like, but it's from 90 something to
4 minutes and five.
>> From 90 seconds to 6 and 12.
>> 6 and Well, you did better than Ian.
Ian's been in the game for 10 years.
Never had those sort of results. So, he
was pretty uh [clears throat] pretty
happy. It was a long phone call. So, it
it happens. And we're slowly getting
we're getting there. What I've managed
to to do and what the book is about is
to try and remove the reliability on
visual effects. Remove the fact that
we're looking at bubbles and put
consistency in charge where we have a
charge power formula. The gentleman
asked how many amps and how many volbs.
Every cell should should be charging
about half a watt per square in of
cathode.
So with a simple power formula, it
doesn't matter how many amps or bolts as
long as you end up with about a half a W
per square in cathode. Any more than
that, you just extra cathode you need
it. Any less than that, you still get
there. It just takes a lot lot longer.
So
between the power formula for how much
do we charge and all charging is based
on the idea of half a watt per square in
per minute.
So if your current is a quarter of a
watt, you charge it for 2 minutes. But
if it's 1 W, you charge it for half a
minute. So a very simple formula saying
what is the right charging current. Now
where people like Alec Schiff used to
say charge a man.
Now is great, but if you've got a 6 in
by one cathode, you've got 18 square in.
If it's 10 in by 2 in round,
you got 30 square in
somewhere around there. So, um, what
I've tried to do is bring down some some
constants so that I can charge this and
I can tell any of you exactly what my
charge power is and what my halfife is,
the time it takes for this cell to
deteriorate to that halfife voltage. And
you can repeat that exactly and you can
share your findings with others and say,
"My engine's running and I hit this hard
drive." As far as bubbles, read the
book. You you don't want them. Um, BS
put this down here.
That's about the latest in in cell
design. Um, it's seamless. Well,
actually that one isn't, but the ones
we're making now are two more seamless.
And the finish is almost like chrome.
They're just mirror finish. That stop
edging. Um, and really stops building up
in the cell. They just go for so much
longer. Um,
now as far as
how many of you have done Joseph?
Okay, that was a few. You've all gone
through looking for these wonderful
stage one and stage two, stage 3s. Could
I interrupt for a minute? the owner of
X153
XPC375.
Could you
please
meditation group was on the next floor?
You're packing them in.
[clears throat]
And um when I did my halfife test and I
do my computer volume and I got all
these results I got them whether I had
bubbles or any bubbles. So they looked
into what make bubbles and they do the
research on where does the rain come
from? How does it happen? How does it
fall? What happens to it? Turns out that
all plants or almost all plants that
have leaves have an immune system.
That's the reason that fungus and mold
doesn't grow on a leaf. Grows on the
ground not on a leaf. They secrete what
what they call a sapion, which is a
natural form of surfactant. It's another
word for soap.
So all of this rain that we get at the
top of the mountain stream that's come
off the rainforest that's come over the
paddics has picked up all of this
natural soap. And it just happens at
that stage to have not too many
pollutants and to meet a lot of our
other requirements.
But
we got this cycle and when we start
using that water in these cells, we get
these bubbles that seem to look great
and they work. Uh they do absolutely
nothing for the production of the energy
or vibration of the cell. So
power [clears throat]
you call a deteriorating battery
but it doesn't deterior
Sorry.
Oh, when we're talking, we're not we're
talking pure voltage.
Uh the the residual voltage, you put a
charge on itself, we'll stick 12 volts
on it for a minute and we wait a little
period of time and we measure that
voltage. Now the case of this cell it
varies from cell to cell but it's pretty
consistent with a particular cell and a
given water.
So that cell with the water that I
process that I use
um the halfife voltage is about 1.2 vol
which means when I charged it I'm not
going to charge it again until the
cell's voltage has dropped off to 1.2
volts.
Uh and this is a very simple formula
that that's in the book where you do two
initial readings. You get the full life
voltage, you get the half life. The full
life is the one minute after a charge.
And this is initial charge when we first
put it together. When you connect back
into one of these cells, the voltage on
it will go up to the full life voltage.
It's kind of uncanny to watch, but all
of a sudden you've got this thing going
up in voltage, not down. Um, and now the
very very crazy thing is current can
come out of them and not into them when
you're charging them back in. If you've
actually got engine running, the
generator's running off this and the
computer connects to charge. I often get
the current coming out, not going in.
So just another
surface area of the cells is what's
creating hydrogen. Um friend here has
got uh the latest design that we sell in
square plates. So you get more surface
area if you put square plates in uh
rather than the round plates. Another
question I've got is um a more exotic
metal. Wouldn't that uh encourage the
hydrogen to be produced? In other words,
if the plates and there were plated with
say nickel, the nickel is going to
encourage more hydrogen production. And
the other thing that that's amazing,
you're charging the water. Is it
possible that you're restoring the
memory back in that water?
>> That I don't know. I really haven't
looked into the memory storage part of
it. I watched the videos. I've seen the
crystals growing, etc. I haven't
researched it. Um, as far as the square
plates or flat plates, the reason that
we have the shape we do with with a
water fuel cell is
cell. We've got cylindricical cylinders
one inside the other. Each of those
effectively becomes a battery. Okay, we
get where it's fully charged about 800 m
volts across each of the gaps. Um, and
half life is about 400 m volts at each
gap. That battery that's inside the cell
tends to stop the
that battery that's in the cell tries to
stop the material from returning back
into the water. So what the neutrals
actually do uh act as as a barrier to
keep the charge within the cell.
So if we go to square plates, we really
don't have the same setup and we can't
keep it as charge. Having said that, you
can put an external control voltage on
it and keep it charged without neutrals.
You can build one of these and make it
work without neutrals. It's just harder.
So you can have as as many neutral
positions in a square
separated from each other.
>> If they're flat parallel plates, the
problem is that we're accumulating
detium on one plate on one end only and
we need a mechanism to attract that off
of the metal and out of the environment
without going back to the cathode. The
construction of this is just ideal for
doing that. And when you're in a flat
plate environment, you really can't stop
that. And it's much harder to stop the
cathode effective cathode in plate from
leaking through all the others. Unless
you try to convert it by voice or
something into a Joe cell, but it's not
going to work as easily. Uh with such a
simple format, there isn't one.
What was the other part of your three?
Yeah, the nickel
never looked at nickel looked at nickel
a very exotic sort of material and it
does encourage in certain um conditions
gas production.
>> The nice thing with stainless is that
when we get to these mirror finishes we
don't get itching. It's fairly dense
metal. Uh people have had a lot of
success with aluminium especially
aluminium tops. Um, anyone here made an
aluminium cell or an aluminium top cone?
Nothing. You have. You have. Okay. Both
have any Well, you've had success. Did
you have any success with yours? No.
Okay.
>> The key was the aluminium.
>> Yeah.
>> The advantage of aluminium uh is that
being a soft metal that deteriorates it
and migrates through it very easily.
as the angle and and I've heard a lot of
people talk about pyramid tops, cone
tops, 45°. I've bought them, I've made
them, I've tried every one of them, and
I haven't measured any difference to a
flat top. And I'm not saying there isn't
a difference, but personally, there
there's been no operational difference
for me personally over a straight flat
top. And the flat tops about a tenth of
the price to make as of even something
like one of those tops, which is 8 mil
thick.
uh a lot easier to make. Um
the direction that I'm starting to go
now and Bob and I were talking about
about this couple of days ago was
laminations where the water surface is
in contact with a half a mill of
stainless that's there to uh for the
electrolysis to stop corrosion itching
all the things aluminium has but
literally aluminium [clears throat]
bonded to the stainless so that we've
got the um lower density the structure
for the dutium to migrate through.
It's just a case of getting the numbers
right, getting getting the thickness
right, getting it working. And you got
to try these.
>> What was interesting was the aluminum
tops which I made cuz they were solid
machine
tops. Um [clears throat] that after
after a while the cell was operating for
a while the the actual alum that was
subjected to the inside of the cell
forms a almost black sort of pentite
coating on it.
>> Okay,
>> which is very hard and is nonconductive.
there was not
and and that was also when the cell was
at it full effect and when it was once
[clears throat]
you've got copper in it where you
separate the copper from the aluminium
uh you find a lot of green
wouldn't be green and and this was
totally non nonconductive
was not green.
No matter it was like
excuse me with the car that
uh yes it was. Yeah. Yeah. Actually I
grab my center
>> and then
there neutrals.
>> Yes I had neutral.
about
what I what I would invite people with
you to do that have worked on Joe within
one sec um share with me if you could
what successes you've had and what
variations I spent some years in my shed
knowing nobody that worked with these I
read little bits on the internet came
across Bob absolutely by some tools one
time um and and got to know him and
therefore meet some of you and others in
in the
But I have very little hands on with
other people's views and therefore
things like the aluminium tops or
graphite centers. They're things I
haven't explored because there's a limit
to what I can do in a [music] day. Um
but I'd like that feedback. I don't need
to reinvent. If you tried something that
didn't work, it saved me a lot of time.
If you tried something that had positive
results, help me in that direction.
Now,
sorry. What color is this showing on
[music]
any
brown or maybe black?
>> Cuz I because I run it out of fuel.
I turn the fuel off. Literally put my
hand over the end of the car, pull it a
few times. So the first time I turn the
ignition on, she's saying we should
flood. It's not funny.
>> The only thing I was asking for is that
you know me and the motors have been
running perfect just conventional rings.
>> Sorry,
>> they running perfect still rings or saw
everyone runs conventional rings.
>> That's just I don't know about the
piston
rings. What I'm asking is if on that
implosion that you're saying is maybe
that maybe it's pulling a fraction of
oil vapor up that it's actually
partially using that as
>> I have little doubt. Well, I don't know
about about fuel because the oil level
certainly does not go down. So my same
>> if it's that my gladly buy all petrol
GTX,000
the combination was you saying that
starting from
>> yeah it could well be with an
endothermic reaction where we got this
inflation and I think that's really why
they had no compression with general
said that it should be kicking back just
occasionally
with Ken Occasionally I'll pull it and
and this is like one in the hundth ball
and it kicks back and what you know
about it's enormous. It's huge. Uh most
of the time there's just no compression.
So that implosion that starts must
logically take oil past the rings. We
must be consuming some oil. But I've
never had to replace oil in it at all.
Well, I I just recall that when Bruce is
Bruce there or you were there when I
gave myself to you and you might recall
what I tell the story what happened to
your car was was the oil.
>> Yeah. When um was sold early
when I used it on the car, the actual uh
exhaust went really oily. It was that
bad that uh when I pulled up a traffic
lights, you could you couldn't
[clears throat] see what was behind you.
It was as though similar to if you break
a ring, crack a ring or something. It
was that much.
>> The explosion was sucking oil up past
the rings and and
>> burn.
The interesting thing was that um Joe
had said previously that if you have any
problems, get a lead, go from the
positive of your battery and just arc it
onto the block and it will get rid of
the charge. And I did that and instantly
the oil smoke stopped. But it came back
over a period of a couple of weeks. It
came back again. I arked it and went
away again. In the end, I took the cell
off and it still did it. And it was only
after I drained the water out of the
radiator and the block and put fresh
water back in that the oil oil smoke
problem didn't reoccur.
Okay.
>> Well, first of all, thank you for
telling me that 6 months ago because you
saved my
tool
came over one evening 25 or 6 months
ago. Uh, I had a cell on on the van, not
for a long time. Um, we done a couple of
trips and I took the cell off the van
and a couple of the effects didn't go
away. It used to go into city finally at
um, how many RPM? 200. Yeah. Just just
way slight lower than it should have
been to the point the ignition light
come on. So the light side
was already going [clears throat]
and it it did this where it felt like it
for a long time. I couldn't stop it. I
just could not stop this thing from
dropping off into absolutely smooth. So
smooth. Smoother than normal 800 RPM.
Just down [clears throat] it goes. And
Bob's got his head up there and he's got
his ear on the exhaust pipe, but it's
running as smooth as would be. And I
think Bruce, you were the one that told
me to zap the crank. And I did want to
zap the crank as normally. Thanks for a
normal vehicle, Bruce.
>> Anyone else? Uh uh 3116 by the way has
between 3 and 6% copper.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> So could we be using that?
What we're doing is is well do we need
do we need to use anything else? We we
believe deterior is our energy. It
certainly has
enough energy. An eighth of a grand for
1200 L of petrol. That's pretty powerful
stuff. Um I've got another video here
which if you wish to see it's 10 minutes
long. It was a presentation by Barry
Hook. Uh it looks at the Joe settle and
perhaps back in the early days uh he
spent time with Joe and had access to
Joe cell talks about what he found. He
concluded that it may be deteriorating.
That's how I originally got to thinking
about it. Then when I learned about
endothermics and so on, it fits. Uh but
he also talks about the the power of
deterium. A thousand times more energy
in deteriorum than uranium which is
powerful stuff you know
it's about a million times more than
petrol some crazy crazy formulation
energy but you don't take those numbers
just the proportions.
Yeah but I'm just trying to make some
sense of physics and chemistry. Yes,
there is an enormous amount of energy
healing, but that only when uh fuses
performing
and we're talking about a a reaction
that normally takes place
and and huge experiments of fusion have
been very difficult
and to step back to try and make some
sense Because the only way I can see
deterior being formed is that you get
atomic hydrogen that is not molecular
but atomic hydrogen for initially
normally in the presence of other
then electron
um which is somehow
uh join with another spare hydrogen
presumably another atomic
The net result of that should be a net
positive charge on the cell. Have you
noticed that? The other question is I'm
trying to figure out is the only way I
can see this run unless we're going for
reaction
anything.
Um so that's
the case. uh my thing that's got nucleus
perhaps it's actually
nitrogen and oxygen
that's more like yes so that's why I
asked the question about exhaust gas so
>> I never have I don't have
uh there is I didn't bring in the Barry
tapes he talks about
guys name
experiments on HH gener ation
environment
where where they were able to and they
measured 350% increases in helium in the
exhaust while we're in the car.
So there's there generation which
supports all the rest of it as far as
creating the detium. I think it's
accepted knowledge. The Germans did it
in World War II. You just keep charging
water, you get material.
>> That that was a convention electroly
and so it seems to be more comes out.
Then you burn that water
from the process. The amount of material
in this mattress is extremely small.
>> That's there, but we don't think we can
make detium
to occur as an electron and a neutron.
>> Well, have to combine those and then
latch them on.
>> Yeah. So, right on the wall of our cell,
we separated hydrogen and oxygen.
Oxygen's got the neutrons. You got heaps
of electrons.
>> Well, that would be an unstable oxygen.
>> Not necessarily.
I don't know if that's a state or not.
>> I don't know either.
>> You're a bit of my knowledge here. I'm a
humble cell builder.
>> My guess is coming from the electron.
>> Okay.
>> That was from
don't know. I really don't. I mean, if
there's specific questions of that type,
I'm happy to Google them and try and
help. You work through them. But to be
truthful, it's not chemistry is not my
field. I didn't know what deterior never
heard of it. It's something where you
hear, you look, you Google, you live on
the internet and you research. How do we
lose compression? Endothermic reactions
give you compression. What can cause
that? Then we work back to somebody
else's suggestion. Did you nitrogen? So,
you get it from both ends. And the other
thing is an object one of uh
my books. This is
the book. Um
don't mention this in the book and
didn't go on until we were just talking.
This is process and the water in a fish
tank. It's an ionization mole charging
process I came up with that gets the
water just right every time. One side of
the tank is always about 10% higher in
the water level than the other. But
there's a hole between the two parts. So
one side's about 10% heavier than the
other and deterior%
heavier
supports that we're making it. And the
figure it's not a mention of it in
there, but I've seen it a thousand
times. So
sort of unexplained
scientifically
happening is just that water.
It's come back from from there was a an
article in the in the local paper which
the hospital is now using um electrolyed
water as clean agent. Now there's many
other other cleaning products and they
find that that is the best cleaning
of thing that they can use that just
basically removes everything which is
fishing part of ioniz membrane with
electrode either side of the membrane
can't be that boring
with an ionizer on either side of the
membrane. What we do is we uh basically
break down water molecule from 13
modules six. Now we end up with a
proportion of those molecules that are
alkaline and the others acidic. Uh in
Japan all hospitals they drink the
alkaline water
you can buy machines for it but it's
standard that they drink the alkaline
for health purpose. You go to a Japanese
hospital
water it's alkaline ionized water and
they clean all the hospital stuff up
with positive water. So
>> yeah,
>> when you're running on the engine,
did you record any of the
um I don't have a thermal
gauge? I guess I had a friend that
exhaust.
>> No, you do get it on the on well the
highest point of combustion engine.
That's where the flame's coming out. In
the case of air, there's so much air
being blown over the head. Things aren't
real combustion surface temperature
anymore.
Uh, normally you touch an exhaust just
for a second and you got to burn. She's
up at 730 something. Tell us what's
exhaust 730 something on petrol.
>> It's hot. It's not
that depend on. Did you measure the
outlet tools or
would be about 200?
Well, 70.
I was quite surprised actually when I
saw 70. I thought is that all how the 70
is quite warm when you put your handle
up for birds. It's still way less than
it should be now. How do we not have the
heat? Endothermic reactions absorb heat
taking the heat of the reaction. Uh
personally 70 is the only factual number
I have, the best I've seen. Um, I've
I've read what I believe is credible
information from people talking about
frost and exhaust.
Uh, engines running so cold that they
frost.
Now, if I can get down to 70 where I
shouldn't be, I can't somebody saying
that right down the other end. And if
we've got full reaction, it's consuming
heat. It can also consume ambient heat.
We can get down below.
So can't dismiss it.
>> Yes.
>> A couple questions just on the cell
itself. I top the cap is actually
isolated from the other
>> the top of the cell.
>> Yeah.
>> No.
>> In that actual instance, it's got a
rubber band in there which I don't
normally have in there. Okay. I'm
showing this whole assembly because of
the clamp that goes around the outside
part.
Um,
this is the easiest seal.
That's the top.
And that's got a seal. But from an
energy point of view, we've got this
relative stainless cast touching all
surfaces. So we've got induction in the
same way our goss
neutral tubes in there.
>> Yes.
>> Is there any particular reason why you
only got two and not three or only one?
>> I don't think there's a need to have
more than two.
um all we're doing with neutrals.
Barry Gilton's work found that he
couldn't see a reason why we have
neutrals. As I explained earlier, the
neutrals are the about 400 mill
on each of those neutrals. What that
potential is doing is keeping that
material in the metal on the outside. If
there's nothing else to stop it, if
there's no potential, it's just going to
come back to the cathode and back into a
natural balance. So electrons [music]
are also trying.
So
they just go and keep the balance. Now
having said that, I put it a step
further this week. Um you're all
familiar with the fact that you have a
gap at the uh engine end of your host
pipe or cable or pipe or whatever you
connect. If you have a gap on the
engine,
we don't have a gap here. We can connect
this cable.
absolutely directly hard connected to
the block. Now, we used [music] to have
a gap because 12 volts went on here and
the blocks are ground.
But what I found this week is connect
that solid and put a negative voltage on
the cathode separate supply positive to
the block, negative to the cathode. So,
we're running this on a floating supply.
We no longer need that gap. And boy,
does the energy get out quick. It makes
a huge difference to the way things
work. So just one little simple step
that's not even books
are a month old saying hey [music]
there's more but
no exactly the same instead of having
cell going to the car chassis and up
here we have a separate supply where we
put positive gear which happens to be
connected to the engine and now the
cathode which is needed
doesn't go to the chassis go
12 actually
I think 6 to 12 in and 6 24 hours. So if
you want a little bit more, but I
believe it's a switch flight. Don't
quote that. You have to get the I just
logged on for for what do
you have to switch?
This is the man.
Anyone else? Yes.
>> Over the period of Joe cells, there's
been a lot of talk about insulators. Can
you just tell us what you found be to be
the best with insulators? Uh first, we
don't have external insulators.
Okay. You don't have insulator layers
between this outside neutral and the
circle. That's a big must. make the cath
strong enough to take everything without
having
um
is is I think probably the best having
said that I promoted teflon made teflon
sold teflon sometimes um there's really
not a lot between teflon you know
electrical insulated quite a bit um
insulators by the way people think of
insulator breaking down electronically
it doesn't if you look closely where
it's edging and how it's edging. I think
it's the deterior
back to the center to balance things
back up and there's no cell potential
there in the the water the electrolyte
is simply not where the electro
is and that's why they edge where they
shouldn't edge. So teflon's great. It
does hold it nicely. Really bonds. If
you put them together, it's impossible
to get them apart. You just shouldn't
get it right now. So,
is that it?
What about when you first met you
talking about your band?
What particular
I don't like talking about my I don't
provide these sales for my accounts. I
have to be very honest. You won't see
anything in the book that says put it in
your car. Um I don't think the
technology is reliable enough yet. And
if it's going to pack up and kids on the
ground, it's right for us to own
experimental vehicles, but occasionally
someone else uses the vehicles. Um
humidity is a major thing with the cell.
If it's raining, a running cell will
stop. I often can't start that if it's
raining. And and I think humidity is
something I'm now looking how to make
this this test outcome this problem. I
got to sell it. It's in the book
and I drove over to Meadows which I had
several times. Now my old van is is an
84 camper.
It's a 2 L high convert to a camper.
Things are pretty pretty weak. Um about
40ks is the best way to go up Chambers
Hill Road. Second gear absolutely fl
it was instant.
There was a need to say wow let's go. It
was fun. Um we then drove up to zoo. um
never intend to sell on board had fuel
thinking about the cell my folks on
board son
so I go to the zoo when we came to the
zoo I'm running out of gas so I flipped
the switch and didn't realize that and
suddenly it ran scient
about 100 km later and on the way back I
comment anything fuel this thing's
flying up down heels
now on that realization I went from
skeptic to I'm amazed this really does
happen there's something in this cell
came out but on the bench for lots of
experiments and my friend me was going
on he open the generator take my
generator he said the experiment 3 years
and about a th000 p,000 p starts later I
still generator with one day electric.
But uh the reason I've still got that
generator is I know absolutely
everything that it does. The timing on
it is a is a machined slide
that's top center but actually it's
about
so
exactly what the timing is. I know
everything. When something changes
because of an experiment being done from
tube to cable, I know exactly what the
changes are because it's run hundreds
and hundreds of times consistently. I
got over
here.
[clears throat]
I I think that drying the air drying air
is not a big a big process. Drying huge
volumes of air can be a little harder.
But as I mentioned earlier with with
Bob's thumb over the car couple of
millimeters of hole very very much
running the lights four years ago. So
maybe these engines really just don't
need the
that they're getting might be running on
the super rich things and it's only been
a week week and a half since we did that
started up.
We we couldn't get petrol. God came
over. We said, "Let's start the
generator." Couldn't get petrol to go.
No blockages. Just nothing I could do to
get petrol to flow into that car. And
that's happened before. Build up of
energy. Whatever won't go in. So I said
to Bob, "Let's put our thumb over the
car, block it off, to run nice and
reach." Uh we really never did run
bridge. We could only get the engine to
run with car being blocked off. Just
big thumb. That's what the photo was on
on the video
and it ran. So yeah, part of this
development is we need to condition
my sharpest.
It's going to cost me a fortune replace.
Yeah. Can I do a high flame?
Well, Bob over here said, "Let's have a
coffee while the sales
we we were just doing lots of crazy
tests. It's all right about what we
find, but occasionally you look up to
you and you say, "What will that do?"
But you don't keep reviewing every
aspect of it. You're not truly
researching. You just go in one
direction. So when I connected the power
up to this with that
was a big home top 5 in round.
Uh we left for a long while wasn't even
on charge at the time. Yeah.
few minutes.
Uh well, we don't charge for minutes. We
charge in a lot shorter duration.
Uh and we started
I did and the cell was there and I
simply saw a color change, heard
nothing, felt nothing, looked at Bob and
then looked back and realized the top
was missing off the cell. Looked up and
and that top that cone top, they're
pretty thin. They weigh nothing. It only
broke the uh asbestous, it fractured a
wooden beam that goes through the tree
and it push through.
So that actually traveled 5 ft that cell
with the fiber. Yeah. Just
the cause was really nothing to do with
the cell. Well, except it had a good bit
of hydrogen in there, but it was the
engine, the short.
There was a backfire. Oh yes, that's
right. That's what
I say.
The backfire did cause it. That's why
now every
H flash they're full of glass beads that
made the HH flash won't stop the gas.
Okay. Hydrogen doesn't burn any quick as
well as the oxygen depends on what you
get. So HA flashback absolute must. We
got a cell that accumulated the hydrogen
and on my slide here one of my slide
wires just wore through on the slide
when it came off the top.
We had a point I called the string and I
think it worked out that it sparked
every couple of degrees and one of them
would have been at a point where
straight back up the tube bang I try to
forget that but I'm really uncomfortable
with [clears throat] working with some
of these cells now if they don't flash
the rest I just don't I won't start the
engine very lucky I wasn't killed the
force that it took to do that was just
enorous
so anyway
Not not personally. I spoke to Western
Australia um some time back that
claimed to have a a diesel station in
his power plant uh which his son made a
sale with a car ignition coil housing.
So it's as well from the general pretty
small uh and he played it bank for quite
a period of time. Um firstly they
thought of it as as using extremely
little diesel because the diesel
consumption went down to nothing for
months but then they realized they were
actually out of diesel that kept
running. But I I don't personally I mean
I spoke to you seem quite credible but I
can never experience person.
So anyone else
about there
and I'm afraid you can't because the
cells in bits and I discussed this with
Bob beforehand. We didn't think people
start.
so close that I was kind of wor
over
the uh generator isn't connected up
because I'm an electrician. I've got a
few other people to do a few things, but
that's the only things that have to be
done. Then it can run on gas. Then
Steven can experiment with a water
cooled engine. This is going to be down
your place for quite a while, I think.
You're welcome to use
that's a six uh 6 KVA um generator and a
1200cc
uh that's a 12 just laying at home or
I'll use that one. It's taken a few
months to put it together. I thought
we'll run on gas and get rid of the car
later on and just have the butterfly
because as Joe point I pointed out to
Joe I said you don't really need a
butter but he said I never thought about
that and it's such a simple thing. Why
do we need a car? We don't need a
butterfly. You only let air in. So
that's going to get deleted. And the
aluminium fell. Where is the couple of
gentlemen there? They give me some
aluminium in aluminium the other day.
I'll make a block up.
That's all we're going to hopefully.
There's other things. These gentlemen up
here, they've got a lot of aluminium
spool. What we're hoping to do is to
enase a cell with aluminium sport to see
if it holds more detenting
yourself and presenting your
>> [applause]
>> Yes. Price of the book. The price of the
book is $49.95. Not that come up there
said 99.9 or so. We all thought it was
99, but it was 9,999.
These are $49.95.
Sorry.
>> Gage is right. If anybody
>> right, we'll bring it up. Look, there's
a box of a box of books here and I'm
looking after the sales of it. So, come
and see me after if you want one or down
the line. I've got some business cards.
pretty poor quality one because uh they
forgot to get printed by the boss. So,
right. Well, thanks very much, Stephen.
And um any other questions? Anybody
really want to present something
important? Yes.
>> Bob, as a teaser for the people here
that are new to it, why don't you
mention what sort of car Joe was driving
originally back in the '90s?
>> I didn't ask him,
>> didn't you?
>> No.
>> Wasn't it a Ford Escort?
>> That was one of them. Also, the Rover
V8. That was one of the first ones. Why
don't you mention some of the strange
effects you noticed in the car?
>> Well, which one do you want?
>> The inertial dampening one.
>> Which one?
>> The inertial dampening effect. When he
had a tuned car running, didn't
experience G-forces when you were around
corners.
>> Oh, no, no, no. That's not his car,
>> wasn't it?
>> No, no, no. That's a Scottish gentleman.
He told me where he lived, but that's an
interesting story again. It's supposed
to go around corners without tip over
and also get off the ground. Joe had
been in it, but he wasn't interested.
But I won't go into all that part.
That's another story. And that that may
come later because I think we're playing
with this sort of stuff. You're going to
come across that stuff because that's
what that guy did. He come across that
stuff.
But Joe, that was not Joe's car. He was
not interested. But actually Joe being
for a drive, put his hands under the
wheels. I'd like to know how did they
steer it, how did they stop it, and
things like that. that he said it was
dead smooth over a real rough bit of
corrugated bit. I've actually seen that
bit of I've seen the rams which
they put the tractor on the back of the
the ute with before it went off the
ground. So some straight things here.
Joe's a fantastic bloke really. He's
very open. He doesn't know what it is
but he knows how to handle it which was
be. And I was lucky enough to spend 2
and 1/2 days with another gentleman
here. You spent one week with him and
been in touch with him for a long time.
You've got a video later on I hope to
show not tonight of the dragster that
Joe had soal treated or put a cell on.
And uh Joe showed me different dragster
[music] field too. Very eye opening.
It's not his vehicle though.
But Joe did apparently 14 different
vehicles including a diesel. The diesel
as Steven said must have an ignition.
And you must have still have that spark.
Joe is a very strange he strange person.
He's played with a lot of things and
come across a lot of abnormalities.
Victor's about abnormalities. He knows a
lot of strange things out there. Well,
Joe did all this up with himself too.
There's a lot of abnies and I was
permitted to take 3 days of talking with
Joe and then my uh some friends actually
transpose it to computer. My wife made
some books and a few of you fellas have
read these books. Well, you you
eventually got accepted from another one
of our members sort of thing in the
roundabout way. Eventually, you gave it
back to Joe. He would know all about
that. Anyway, now has anybody else got
something to present now? You've got
some
>> Yeah,
there's
interested in that video.
>> How much?
>> There we go. There's a fire. This one
auction case.
>> Oh, sorry.
You're going to start the auction. So,
has anybody got any stuff? Uh, yes.